(洛杉矶  公元2029年)
1997年8月29日 30亿人口被夺去了性命
Three billion human lives ended on August 29th, 1997.
核大战之后的幸存者...
The survivors of the nuclear fire...
称这场战争为“审判日”
called the war "Judgment Day".
他们活下来只是为了面对新的梦魇...
They lived only to face a new nightmare...
一场与机器间的战争
the war against the machines.
控制着这些机器的电脑 天网...
The computer which controlled the machines, Skynet...
派遣两名终结者穿梭时空
sent two Terminators back through time.
它们的任务: 杀死人类反抗军领袖...
Their mission: to destroy the leader of the human resistance...
约翰康纳 我的儿子
John Connor, my son.
第一位终结者被设定为毁灭我...
The first Terminator was programmed to strike at me...
时间是在1984年...
in the year 1984...
约翰出生之前
before John was born.
它失败了
It failed.
第二名终结者则直接找到约翰本人...
The second was set to strike at John himself...
而当时 他还是个孩子
when he was still a child.
依照惯例 反抗军会单独派遣一名战士...
As before, the resistance was able to send a lone warrior...
一个约翰的保护者
a protector for John.
剩下的问题就是哪一个会先找到他？
It was just a question of which one of them would reach him first.
《终结者2：审判日》
(扫描模式)
("马厩"酒吧 营业中)
(符合概率:99% 完全测量设置)
(条件符合)
我要你的衣服 靴子以及摩托车
I need your clothes, your boots and your motorcycle.
你忘了说"请"
You forgot to say "please".
快把他拖走!
Get him off me!
把刀拔出来!
Pull it out!
给你
Take it.
我不能让你抢走别人的摩托车 小子
Can't let you take the man's wheels, son.
在我轰了你之前 下车
Now, get off before I put you down.
天杀的 别得寸进尺了
That's it, goddamn it.
31区 大卫·雪漫 状况6...
R-31 David, Sherman Code 6...
在第六街桥及圣塔菲附近调查电流干扰现象
at the Sixth Street Bridge and Santa Fe on electrical disturbance.
104 31区 大卫
Ten-four, R-31 David.
(JMA查询:约翰康纳)
(青少年自动索引数据库 姓名查询:约翰康纳 种族:白人；年龄:10岁)
(拘留记录:J 66455705 非法闯入 商店盗窃 破坏公物)
(生母:康纳 生父:不详 法定监护人:托德与珍妮 地址:艾蒙德街南19828号)
约翰进来把你的猪窝清理干净
John, get in there and clean up that pigsty of yours.
你的养父母都是混球 对吧?
Your foster parents are kind of dicks, huh?
我发誓 我真是受够了那该死的小鬼
I swear, I have had it with that goddamn kid.
- 他甚至连我的问话都不回答  - 甜心 别挡住
- He won't even answer me anymore.  - Honey, move.
可以高抬贵臀 帮我个忙吗?
Would you get off your butt and help me?
- 托德!  - 干嘛?
- Todd!  - What?
他的房间已经一个月没清理了
He hasn't cleaned that room of his in a month.
喔 要紧事是吧 等一下 我马上处理
Oh, it's an emergency. Hang on. I'll get right on it.
走吧
Come on.
给我滚进来 照你妈说的话去做
Get your ass inside. Do what your mother tells you.
她才不是我妈呢 托德
She's not my mother, Todd.
(皮斯卡德罗州立医院 加州)
接下来的这个病人很有趣
This next patient is interesting.
我观察这一案例已经好几年了
I've been following the case for years.
现年29岁的女性...
A 29-year-old female...
经诊断为严重的情感失调 所引起的精神分裂症患者
diagnosed as acute schizo-affective disorder.
一般症状:沮丧 焦虑 暴力倾向...
The usual indicators: depression, anxiety, violent acting out...
有被害妄想症
delusions of persecution.
其妄想症的架构相当的独特
The delusional architecture is fairly unique.
她认为一种叫终结者的机器人...
She believes that a machine called the Terminator...
外形犹如人类一般 穿越时空...
which looks human, of course, was sent back through time...
- 被派来杀死她  - 这故事真奇特
- to kill her.  - That's original.
同时 她孩子的父亲...
And also that the father of her child...
是一名被派遣来保护她的士兵
was a soldier sent back to protect her.
他同样是来自于未来
He was from the future too.
如果我没记错的话 那是在2029年
The year 2029, if I remember correctly.
我们到了
And here we are.
早安 莎拉
Morning, Sarah.
早安 西伯曼医生 膝盖还好吧?
Good morning, Dr. Silberman. How's the knee?
好多了
Fine, Sarah.
几星期前 她拿了我的笔...
She stabbed me in the kneecap...
刺进我的膝盖骨
with my pen a few weeks ago.
多次试图逃跑
Repeated escape attempts.
我们继续吧 好吗?
Let's move on, shall we?
我不喜欢看到 病人把房间弄得这么乱
I don't like to see the patients disrupting their rooms like this.
- 看着她把药吃了  - 好的 交给我吧
- See she takes her Thorazine.  - Sure. I'll take care of it.
该吃药啦 康纳
It's time to take your meds, Connor.
留给你自己吧
You take it.
知道吗 你最好老实点...
Now you know you gotta be good...
今天下午是回访观察日
because you're up for review this afternoon.
我不吃 我不想惹麻烦
I'm not taking it, Dougie. I don't want any trouble.
一点也不麻烦
Ain't no trouble.
对 给她上电击
Yeah, zap her.
最后关照 甜心
Last call, sugar.
做个好梦
Sweet dreams.
(警车35679 "保护和服务")
你们是约翰康纳的法定监护人吗?
Are you the legal guardian of John Connor?
是的 警官 他又做什么了?
That's right, Officer. What's he done now?
- 我可以跟他谈谈吗?  - 如果他在的话 当然可以
- Could I speak with him, please?  - You could if he were here.
不过他今早骑摩托车出去了 现在可能在任何地方
He took off on his bike this morning, so he could be anywhere.
你们有约翰的照片吗?
Do you have a photograph of John?
有 当然有 你等一下
Yeah, sure, hold on.
可以告诉我是什么事吗?
Gonna tell me what this is about?
我只需要问他几个问题
I just need to ask him a few questions.
看上去是个好漂亮的孩子 不介意我留下这张照片吧?
He's a good-looking boy. Do you mind if I keep this picture?
不 拿去吧 今早有个男人也找他
No, go on. There was a guy here this morning looking for him too.
没错 一个骑摩托车的大个子
Yeah, a big guy on a bike.
这两件事有关联吗?
Has that got something to do with this?
不 甭担心那个人
No, I wouldn't worry about him.
感谢你们的合作
Thanks for your cooperation.
现在 请插入你偷来的卡
Please insert your stolen card now.
PIN码
PIN number.
快点 你弄得太久了
Hurry up. This is taking too long.
快 宝贝
Go, baby.
好呀
All right.
- PIN码 9003  - 你从哪边学来的?
- PIN number 9003.  - Where'd you learn this stuff from?
从我妈那里 我是说我亲妈
From my mom. My real mom, I mean.
领出300元
Withdraw 300 bucks.
快点 宝贝 快来!
Come on, baby. Come on!
- 好极了!  - 嘿 成功了
- Yes!  - Hey, it worked.
好来 好容易得来的钱 走吧!
All right. Easy money. Come on!
是啊! 小菜一碟
Yes! Piece of cake.
- 这就是她吗?  - 对
- Is that her?  - Yes.
她挺酷的 嗯?
She's pretty cool, huh?
才不呢 她是个十足的疯子
No, she's a complete psycho.
那就是为何她会在皮斯卡德罗 那可是一间精神病院 知道吧?
That's why she's at Pescadero. It's a mental institute. OK?
她曾经想炸掉一座电脑工厂 但是中弹被逮捕
She tried to blow up a computer factory but got shot and arrested.
不会吧 该死的
No shit.
她是个彻底的失败者
She's a total loser.
走吧 花钱去
Come on. Let's go spend some money.
莎拉
Sarah...
莎拉 醒醒
Sarah, wake up.
卡友
Kyle
你已经死了
You're dead.
我们的儿子在哪儿？
Where's our son, Sarah?
他们把他从我身边抢走了
They took him away from me.
- 他现在是敌人的目标啊  - 我知道
- He's the target now.  - I know.
他孤身一人 你必须保护他
He's all alone and you have to protect him.
我知道
I know.
你告诉我 我到底该怎么做啊
You tell me how I'm supposed to do that.
他甚至不再相信我了
He doesn't even believe me anymore.
- 我失去他了  - 你很坚强 莎拉
- I've lost him.  - You're strong, Sarah.
比你想像的还要坚强
Stronger than you ever thought you could be.
战士 站起来!
On your feet, soldier!
我爱你 莎拉
I love you, Sarah.
至死不渝
I always will.
我需要你
I need you.
我会一直陪伴你
I'll always be with you.
还记得那段讯息吗?
Remember the message?
未来尚未定数
The future is not set.
命运并不存在 要靠自己创造
There is no fate but what we make for ourselves.
和我在一起
Stay with me.
这世界马上要到最后的日子了
There's not much time left in the world, Sarah.
卡友 别走!
Kyle, don't go!
卡友
Kyle!
它就像是一只巨大的闪光灯...
It's like a giant strobe light...
向我的眼睛直烧而来
burning right through my eyes.
不知为何 我仍然看得到
Somehow I can still see.
天呀
Oh, God.
我们都知道这梦境每晚一直重复着
We know the dream's the same every night.
- 为什么还要我...  - 请继续
- Why do I have to...  - Please continue.
孩子们像烧掉的纸
Children look like burnt paper.
焦黑
Black.
动也不动
Not moving.
然后冲击波袭向他们
And then the blast wave hits them.
而他们就像叶子掉落般的飞散
And they fly apart like leaves.
梦见...
Dreams...
战争 世界末日等的梦境...
of cataclysm, the end of the world...
都是比较常见的
are very common.
这不是梦 你这白痴 这是真的
It's not a dream, you moron. It's real.
- 我知道它确实发生的日期  - 我相信你觉得那挺有真实感
- I know the date it happens.  - I'm sure it feels very real to you.
在1997年8月29日...
On August 29, 1997...
那天你也会感受到他妈的真实感!
it's gonna feel pretty fuckin'real to you too!
每个人都赤身露体 两百万倍的防晒指数 每个人都会大难临头 明白吗?
Anybody not wearing two-million sunblock is gonna have a real bad day. Get it?
老天啊 你认为你现在是安全的活着
God, you think you're safe and alive.
其实你已经死了 每个人都是!
You're already dead. Everybody!
他或是你 你们早都死了
Him. You. You're dead already.
这整个地方 你看见的 任何东西都已消失殆尽!
This whole place, everything you see is gone!
你才是个活在他妈梦里的人 因为我知道这件事发生了!
You're the one living in the fucking dream, 'cause I know it happened!
它发生了!
It happened!
我现在觉得好多了
I feel much better now.
思绪清楚
Clearer.
没错 你的态度最近...
Yes, your attitude has been...
改善了不少
much improved lately.
有件事帮助我确定目标...
It's helped me to have a goal...
期待着它能实现
something to look forward to.
是什么呢?
What is that?
哦 你说...
Well, you said...
如果6个月内我的情形有改善...
that if I showed improvement after six months...
你会把我转移到看守较松的监房...
you would transfer me to the minimum security wing...
并且容许访客见我
and I could have visitors.
现在已经6个月了...
Well, it's been six months...
还有...
and...
我很期待可以见到我儿子
I was looking forward to seeing my son.
我懂了
I see.
现在我们回到你所说的 那些终结者机器人上
Let's go back to what you were saying about those Terminator machines.
现在你不认为有这种东西了?
Now you think they don't exist?
他们并不存在
They don't exist.
我现在明白了
I know that now.
但是很多时候你告诉过我 关于...
But you've told me on many occasions about how you crushed one...
你在液压机里压扁的那个
in a hydraulic press.
如果我曾做过这件事 现场应该会留下证据
If I had, there would have been some evidence.
他们会在工厂里发现东西
They would have found something at the factory.
我懂了
I see.
所以你不再相信某公司销毁了证据?
So you don't believe anymore that the company covered it up?
当然 他们为何要这么做?
No. Why would they?
我们在这新位置试试看
Let's try a new position right there.
戴森先生?
Mr. Dyson?
材料组正在测试另外一个...
The materials team is running another...
- 戴森先生  - 什么事?
- Mr. Dyson.  - Yes?
材料组今天下午要测试另一种系列
The materials team is running another series this afternoon.
你还没签收...它
You have to sign for the...it.
- 你得去签收  - 好的 来吧 我会的
- You have to sign it out.  - Okay. Come on. I'll get it.
听着 戴森先生 我知道我才来不久 但是我在想你是否知道...
Listen, Mr. Dyson. I know I haven't been here long, but I was wondering if you know...
知道什么?
Know what?
你是否知道'它'是从哪来的
If you know where "it" came from.
我问过相同的问题 你知道他们怎么说吗?
I asked them the same question once. You know what they told me?
别多问
Don't ask.
- 戴森先生 早安  - 还好吧?
- Good morning, Mr. Dyson.  - How's it going?
插入钥匙 左转 倒数三
Insert key. Left on three.
二 一 转
Two, one, turn.
- 老婆 孩子都好吧?  - 很好 谢谢
- How are the wife and kids?  - Great. Thanks.
医生 你认为如何?
So what do you think, Doctor?
我看来是否有改善了?
I have shown improvement, haven't I?
呃 莎拉 问题就在这里
Well, Sarah, here's the problem.
我知道你有多聪明
I know how smart you are.
你只是告诉我 我想听到的
You're just telling me what I want to hear.
我不认为你今天说的那些是实话
I don't think you really believe what you're telling me today.
如果我把你转至守备较松的监房 你又会想逃跑
If I put you in minimum security, you'll just try to escape again.
你必须让我见我儿子
You have to let me see my son.
求你了
Please.
他身处极度危险中 只有我才能保护他
He's in great danger. He's naked without me.
如果我可以打一个电话...
If I could make a phone call...
恐怕不行 至少暂时是这样
I'm afraid not. Not for a while.
看来我没什么选择 只能建议审查委员...
I don't see any choice but to recommend to the review board...
你必须在此多留6个月了
that you stay here for another six months.
我要杀了你 你这混蛋!
I'll kill you, you son of a bitch!
你这混蛋!
You son of a bitch!
注射10CC的镇静剂!
Ten CCs of sodium amobarbital, stat!
你不知道你干了什么好事!
You don't know what you're doing!
拿一些捆绑带过来!
Get some restraints in here now!
你不知道你干了什么好事!
You don't know what you're doing!
真是个模范市民
Model citizen.
(身份确认 目标寻获)
你刚好错过他 15分钟前他在这里
You just missed him. He was here 15 minutes ago.
- 他正要去购物中心 对吗?  - 对
- He was going to the Galleria, right?  - Yeah.
购物中心?
The Galleria?
我去换些铜板 马上就来 好吗?
I'm gonna get some quarters. I'll be back, all right?
- 哦 不!  - 小女孩 你们认识约翰康纳吗？
- Oh, no!  - Girls, do you know John Connor?
不认识
No.
喂 你认识这个人吗?
Hey, do you know this guy?
不 我不认识他
Nah, I don't know him.
- 约翰  - 现在别吵
- John.  - Not now.
有个警察正在找你 快看
There's this cop scoping for you. Check it out.
- 他就在那里  - 快闪吧 老兄
- He's right over there.  - Split, man.
- 快走  - 好
- Just go.  - Yeah.
我看到那小子...
I saw that kid...
你不可以进这里来!
You're not supposed to be in here!
趴下
Get down.
先生 你没事吧?
Mister, are you all right?
没事吧?
You all right?
快呀!
Come on!
该死!
Goddamn!
好了 暂停一下 停车
Okay, time-out. Stop the bike.
暂停 拜托 停车
Time out. Come on, stop the bike.
我的老天 别搞错了
Holy shit. Now, don't take this the wrong way.
- 你是个终结者 对吧?  - 没错
- You are a Terminator, right?  - Yes.
赛博坦系统 101型
Cyberdyne Systems, Model 101 .
该死
Holy shit.
你真的是真的
You're really real.
我是说...
I mean...
你身体里是一部机器 对吧?
You're like a machine underneath, right?
但是外表像真人?
But alive outside?
我是一个神经机械有机体
I'm a cybernetic organism.
一层活体组织覆盖在金属内骨骼上
Living tissue over metal endoskeleton.
这可令我紧张了
This is intense.
好好想清楚 约翰 好吧
Get a grip, John. Okay.
你不是来杀我的
You're not here to kill me.
这部份我自己理解出来了 那你来这干什么?
I figured that part out for myself. So what's the deal?
我的任务是来保护你
My mission is to protect you.
是吗? 谁派你来的?
Yeah? Who sent you?
你派我来的
You did.
距今35年后 你将我重新设置...
35 years from now, you reprogrammed me...
前往这个时代 来保护你
to be your protector here, in this time.
喔 太玄乎了
Oh, this is deep.
那另一个家伙也是个终结者 没错吧?
So this other guy, he's a Terminator like you, right?
与我不相同 它是T-1000 型号更先进
Not like me. A T-1000, advanced prototype.
你是说比你还先进?
You mean more advanced than you are?
对 有模仿能力的技术合金
Yes. A mimetic poly-alloy.
那是什么鬼玩意?
What the hell does that mean?
液态金属
Liquid metal.
我们要去哪里?
Where are we going?
我们必须马上出城 避免当局追查
We have to get out of the city immediately and avoid the authorities.
我得回家 收拾一些行李
I gotta stop by my house. I wanna pick up some stuff.
要求否决 T-1000肯定会在那里等你
Negative. The T-1000 would definitely try to reacquire you there.
- 你确定?  - 如果我 我就会
- You sure?  - I would.
听着 托德和珍妮虽然是混球...
Look, Todd and Janelle are dicks...
但是我得警告他们
but I gotta warn 'em.
可恶 你有25美分吗?
Shit. You got a quarter?
- 喂  - 珍妮 是我
- Hello.  - Janelle, it's me.
- 约翰？  - 一切平安吧?
- John?  - Is everything all right?
- 你们还好吗?  - 当然 甜心 我们很好
- Are you guys okay?  - Sure, honey, everything's okay.
- 你没事吧?  - 对 我没事
- Are you all right?  - Yeah, l'm fine.
约翰 现在很晚了 我开始有点担心你
John, it's late. I was beginning to worry about you.
如果你快点回家 我们可以一起吃晚餐
If you hurry home, we can sit down and have dinner together.
我正在烧炖牛肉
I'm making beef stew.
不对劲 她从来不会对我这么好
Something's wrong. She's never this nice.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
那只该死的狗在乱叫个什么劲呀?
What the hell is the goddamn dog barking at?
闭嘴 你这没用的垃圾!
Hey, shut up, you worthless piece of shit!
狗真的叫得很大声
The dog's really barking.
你要告诉那小鬼丢掉那只杂种狗
You were gonna tell the kid to get rid of that fucking mutt.
约翰 现在很晚了 别让我太担心
John, honey, it's late. Please don't make me worry.
他会不会已经在那里了?
Could he already be there?
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
- 我在这 我很好  - 你确定没事吗?
- I'm right here. I'm fine.  - Are you sure you're all right?
- 狗叫什么名字?  - 麦克斯
- What's the dog's name?  - Max.
嘿 珍妮 沃菲怎么了?
Hey, Janelle. What's wrong with Wolfie?
我听到它在叫 它没事吧?
I can hear him barking. Is he okay?
沃菲没事  它好得很
Wolfie's fine, honey. Wolfie's just fine.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
你的养父母死了
Your foster parents are dead.
我需要点时间静静
I need a minute here.
你是说这东西可以模仿任何它摸过的物体?
You're telling me that this thing can imitate anything it touches?
任何它以身体接触采样的
Anything it samples by physical contact.
举个例子
Get real.
它也能乔装成一包香烟?
It could disguise itself as a pack of cigarettes?
不 仅能模仿体积相同的东西
No, only an object of equal size.
为何不直接变成炸弹来干掉我?
Why not just become a bomb or something to get me?
它不能变成复杂的机械
It can't form complex machines.
枪及爆炸物都有化学物质和可变成份
Guns and explosives have chemicals, moving parts.
它模仿不了
It doesn't work that way.
- 但是它可以形成固态的金属  - 比如什么?
- But it can form solid metal shapes.  - Like what?
刀子或尖锐的武器
Knives and stabbing weapons.
这些是1984年西高地警局里...
These were taken by a video surveillance camera...
监视器拍下来的照片
at the West Highland Police Station in 1984.
当晚他杀了17名警员
He killed 17 police officers that night.
有家庭...
Men with families...
有小孩的人
children.
这些则是在瑞西达的一间购物中心...
These were taken at a mall in Reseda...
今天拍到的
today.
康纳小姐 我们晓得 你知道这人是谁
Miss Connor, we know you know who this guy is.
我坐在这里告诉你 你的儿子失踪了...
Look, I just sat here and told you that your son is missing...
而他的养父母均被谋杀
that the foster parents have been murdered.
我们知道这家伙牵涉其中
We know this guy's involved.
这对你来说没任何意义? 你不在乎吗?
Doesn't that mean anything to you? Don't you care?
我们是在浪费时间
We're wasting our time.
走吧
Let's go.
抱歉 两位
Sorry, guys.
随着时间的流逝 她渐渐变得与现实脱节了
She's grown more disconnected from reality as time goes on.
我恐怕她现在帮不上忙
I'm afraid she can't help us now.
如果她完全清醒 而且能提供 任何消息 我会通知你们的
If she clears at all and can give us anything, I'll call you.
好吧
Sure.
道格拉斯 带她回房
Douglas, take her back to her room.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
走吧 甜心 回房间了
Come on, sweetheart. Let's go.
你知道吗...
You see...
我们在尼加拉瓜及类似的地方住了一阵子
we spent a lot of time in Nicaragua and places like that.
有一段时间 她跟一个曾经戴过绿色贝雷帽的疯子在一起...
For a while there, she was with this crazy ex-Green Beret guy...
研究枪枝
running guns.
之后又有一些家伙
Then there were some other guys.
她会搭上任何她能从中学习的人...
She'd shack up with anybody she could learn from...
这样她就能教我如何成为 一个伟大的军事领袖
so she could teach me how to be this great military leader.
然后她被逮捕了
Then she gets busted.
好像是说 "抱歉 小子 你妈是疯子 你不知道吗?"
It's like, "Sorry, kid, your mom's a psycho. Didn't you know?"
就像我所相信的一切 都是狗屎堆起来的
Like everything I've been brought up to believe is all made-up bullshit.
我因此而恨她
I hated her for that.
但是她所说的每件事都是真的
But everything she said was true.
她知道实情...
She knew...
但没人相信她...
and nobody believed her...
甚至连我也不信
not even me.
听着 我们得救她出来
Listen. We gotta get her out of there.
要求否决 T-1000可能已成功潜入病院...
Negative. The T-1000's highest probability for success now...
它将模仿莎拉康纳的形象 并等你去找她
will be to copy Sarah Connor and wait for you to make contact with her.
好极了 那她会怎样?
Great. What happens to her?
典型的做法 被模仿的对象将会被终结
Typically, the subject being copied is terminated.
糟糕! 你为什么不早说? 我们现在得马上赶过去!
Shit! Why didn't you tell me? We gotta go right now!
要求否决 这不是我的优先任务
Negative. It's not a mission priority.
去你的! 救她是我的优先任务!
Fuck you! She's a priority to me!
该死! 你是哪里不对劲了? 该死! 救命!
Goddamn it! What's your problem? Damn it! Help!
这对我们的任务没有帮助
This does not help our mission.
把这疯子拉开! 救命!
Get this psycho off of me! Help!
我被绑架了! 把这疯子拉走!
I'm being kidnapped! Get this psycho off of me!
放开我!
Let me go!
你干嘛这样?
Why the hell did you do that?
因为你叫我这样做
Because you told me to.
什么?
What?
我说的话你得照做?
You have to do what I say?
那是我的任务指令之一
That's one of my mission parameters.
证明给我看 单脚站立
Prove it. Stand on one foot.
好呀!
Yes!
酷喔 专属于我的终结者
Cool. My own Terminator.
你还好吧 小子?
You okay, kid?
快滚吧 笨蛋
Take a hike, bozo.
我们走吧 老兄
Let's get outta here, man.
去你的 你这小蠢猪!
Fuck you, you little dipshit!
蠢猪?
Dipshit?
把脚放下
Put your leg down.
- 你刚才说我是只蠢猪?  - 别费力气去帮这个无懒
- Did you call moi a dipshit?  - Just trying to help this punk.
抓住这家伙
Grab this guy.
放开我!
Get him off of me!
现在谁才是蠢猪呀...
Now who's the dipshit...
你个大蛮牛
you jock douche bag
快把枪放下 现在!
Put the gun down now!
- 快滚吧!  - 走吧 我们快跑!
- Get outta here!  - Come on. Let's split!
你差点杀了那个人!
You were gonna kill that guy!
当然 我是个终结者
Of course. I'm a Terminator.
仔细听我说 好吗?
Listen to me very carefully, okay?
你已经不再是个终结者了 知道吗?
You're not a Terminator anymore, all right?
懂不懂?
You got that?
你不可以随便杀人
You just can't go around killing people.
为什么?
Why?
什么为什么? 因为你就是不可以
What do you mean, why? 'Cause you can't.
为什么?
Why?
因为你就是不可以 知道吗? 在这方面相信我好了
Because you just can't, OK? Trust me on this.
听好 我得去救我妈
Look. I'm gonna go get my mom.
我命令你 帮助我
I order you to help me.
你们有名患者叫莎拉康纳吗?
You have a Sarah Connor here?
你来得有点晚了 不是吗?
You're runnin' kind of late, aren't you?
他们已经在里面一个小时了
They've been in there for an hour.
稍等一下 我替你通报
Hold on a second. I'll buzz you in.
噢 你的朋友们来了
Oh, here come your friends now.
- 葛文 你要来杯咖啡吗?  - 不用 谢了
- Gwen, you want some coffee?  - No, thanks.
- 要不来杯啤酒?  - 是啊 好啊
- How 'bout a beer?  - Yeah, right.
- 嘿 我拿到了满堂红(三张同点加一对)  - 恭喜你 路易斯
- Hey, I got a full house.  - That's good, Louis.
今天一定是我的幸运日
Must be my lucky day.
关于数字24你是对的
You're right about number 24.
药量增加至250毫克
Increase the medication to 250 milligrams.
同一种吗?
Same kind?
你!
You!
你打断了我的胳膊
You broke my arm.
人体内有215根骨头
There are 215 bones in the human body.
那只是其中一根 别乱动
That's one. Now, don't move.
(液体除草剂 工业浓度 巨毒)
你想做什么？?
What are you going to do?
我们干嘛停下来?
Why do we stop now?
你答应我不会乱杀人 好吗?
You gotta promise me you're not gonna kill anyone, right?
- 好的  - 你发誓?
- Right.  - Swear?
什么?
What?
只管举起手并说'我发誓不再杀人'
Just put up your hand and say, "I swear I won't kill anyone."
我发誓不再杀人
I swear I will not kill anyone.
好 我们走吧
All right. Let's go.
探访时间是星期一至星期五...
Visiting hours is 10:00 to 4:00...
早上10点到下午4点
Monday through Friday.
你究竟在干什么?
What the hell are you doing?
他妈的! 你开枪打我!
You son of a bitch! You shot me!
该死的混蛋!
Crazy bastard!
别再对我开枪 别杀我
Don't shoot me again. Don't kill me.
他会活着的
He'll live.
混蛋!
Son of a bitch!
试着保持冷静
Let's try to remain calm.
开门 不然他就死定了
Open it, or he'll be dead before he hits the floor.
这样行不通的 康纳 放他走
There's no way, Connor. Let him go.
- 把门打开  - 办不到
- Open the door.  - It ain't gonna happen.
别冲动 莎拉 冷静点
Take it easy, Sarah.
这不成 你不是杀手 我不相信你下得了手
It won't work. You're no killer. I don't believe you can do it.
你早就死了 每个人都死了 你知道我相信这件事
You're already dead. Everybody dies. You know I believe it.
所以别惹毛我!
So don't fuck with me!
把门打开!
Open the door!
退后!
Back off!
Get back!
我会把这玩意全打进他体内 我发誓!
I'll pump him full of this shit. I swear!
不准动!
Don't move!
把这鬼东西放下!
Drop the shit!
快照做!
Do it!
进办公室去
Get in the office.
趴在地上 脸朝下 不是说你!
On the floor, face down. Not you!
把门打开
Open the door.
趴到地上 保持门打开
On the floor. Hold it open.
面朝墙壁!
Face the wall!
抓住她!
Get her!
快点! 快开门! 门被锁住了!
Hurry up! Open the door! The door's locked!
动作快! 打开它!
Let's go! Open it!
- 她把钥匙折断了  - 把门打开!
- She broke it off.  - Open it!
绕路过去! 快点! 动作快!
Let's go around! Come on! Move it!
妈 等一下!
Mom, wait!
回来!
Come back here!
- 快去帮她!  - 在这等我
- Help her!  - Wait here.
- 快点!  - 他会杀了我们!
- Hurry up!  - He'll kill us all!
抓紧她
Hold her.
他会杀了我们所有人!
He'll kill us all!
妈 你还好吧? 妈!
Mom, are you okay? Mom!
如果你想活下去的话 就跟我走
Come with me if you want to live.
没事的 妈 他是来帮忙的 没事的
It's okay, Mom. He's here to help. It's OK.
快走
Go.
那是什么东西? 发生了什么事?
What the fuck is it? What the fuck is going on?
蹲下
Get down.
给我下车!
Out of the car!
马上!
Right now!
开车!
Go!
子弹用完了
I'm out.
- 快点  - 拿去
- Come on.  - Here.
重新填弹
Reload.
最后一个弹匣了!
Last one!
坐稳了
Hang on.
装好了!
Ready!
来开车
Here, drive.
后面没人 他没追上来
He's not back there. There's nobody behind us.
- 你没事吧?  - 对
- Are you all right?  - Yeah.
你看得见路吗?
Can you see anything?
我看的一清二楚
I see everything.
(强化视讯模式)
酷
Cool.
过来
Come here.
我说过我没事
I said I was okay.
约翰 你跑到那里很愚蠢
John, it was stupid of you to go there.
你必需更聪明点
God. damn it. You have to be smarter than that.
你差点就被杀了
You were almost killed.
你在想些什么?
What were you thinking?
你不能以身犯险 即使是为了我
You cannot risk yourself, even for me.
懂了吗?
Do you understand?
你太重要了
You're too important.
知道吗?
Do you understand?
但是...
But...
我必须把你救出来 我很抱歉
I had to get you out of that place. I'm sorry.
我不需要你的帮忙 我可以照顾自己
I didn't need your help. I can take care myself.
你的眼睛怎么啦?
What's wrong with your eyes?
没什么
Nothing.
那么 你又是什么来头?
So, what's your story?
你没事吧?
You okay?
没事
Fine.
说起来 这辆摩托车真不错
Say, that's a nice bike.
小点劲 大老粗
Watch it, lug nuts.
听着 你知道该怎么缝合吗?
Listen, do you know what you're doing?
我有人体解剖学的详细资料
I have detailed files on human anatomy.
不赖啊
I bet.
这让你变成更有效率的杀手 对吧?
Makes you a more efficient killer, right?
完全正确
Correct.
你中弹时会觉得痛吗?
Does it hurt when you get shot?
我感应得到伤害 可以称做'疼痛'
I sense injuries. The data could be called "pain."
约翰 帮我照亮
John, help me with the light.
- 这些伤口会愈合吗?  - 会
- Will these heal up?  - Yes.
很好 如果你看起来不像人类 对我们就没多大用处了
Good. If you can't pass for human, you're not much good to us.
你能活多久? 我是指 可以用多久
How long do you live? I mean, last. Whatever.
内藏电池可持续使用120年
A hundred and twenty years with my existing power cell.
你能学些程序未预设的东西吗...
Can you learn stuff that you haven't been programmed with...
然后你就可以...
so you can be...
你知道 更像人...
you know, more human...
而不会总像个呆子?
and not such a dork all the time?
我的中央处理器 具备神经网络 处理程序 是有学习能力的电脑
My CPU is a neural net processor, a learning computer.
但当我们被派遣出来时 天网将其预设为只读
But Skynet presets the switch to read-only when we're sent out alone.
不让你想太多 对吧?
Doesn't want you to do too much thinking, huh?
对
No.
我们能重置这设定吗?
Can we reset the switch?
逆时针旋转两个锁住的圆柱
Rotate the two locking cylinders counterclockwise.
执行
Do it.
然后打开连接护盖
Now open the port cover.
向外拉 开启它
Pull to break the seal.
很好 现在移除震动阻尼配件
Good, now remove the shock-damping assembly.
现在你就可以拿到中央处理器了
You can now access the CPU.
- 看到了吗?  - 看到了
- Do you see it?  - Yes.
抓住中央处理器的基板
Hold the CPU by its base tab.
拉出来
Pull.
你看到开关了吗?
Do you see the pin switch?
不行! 不行!
No! No!
- 别拦着我 John  - 别杀了他
- Out of my way, John.  - Don't kill him.
是它 约翰 不是他 是它
It, John, not him. It.
好吧"它" 但是我们需要"它"
Okay, "It". But we need "It".
仔细听我说 你听好了
Listen to me. You listen.
我们最好靠自己
We're better-off on our own.
但他是我们仅有的证据...
But he's the only proof we have...
有关未来以及那场战役等等
of the future and the war and all that.
也许吧
Maybe.
我不相信它
I don't trust it.
可他是我的朋友 好吗?
But he's my friend, all right?
你不了解 要消灭 这样一个东西有多难...
You don't know what it's like to try to kill one of these things...
如果会出什么意外 现在就是我们 唯一的机会 所以赶快让开!
and if something goes wrong this could be our last chance, so move!
听着 妈妈 如果我将来真会成为那个伟大军事领袖...
Look mom, if I'm ever supposed to be this great military leader...
那也许你应该开始听听我的领导意见了
maybe you should start listening to my leadership ideas once in a while.
因为如果连我的母亲都不肯听...
Because if my own mother won't...
你还能期望别的什么人会听吗?
how do you expect anyone else to?
好吧 就依你说的
All right, play it your way.
(系统中断)
(诊断中)
有什么问题吗?
Was there a problem?
没有
No problem.
一点问题也没有
None whatsoever.
学到点东西了吧?
Are we learning yet?
我们必须离城市越远越好
We have to get as far away from the city as possible.
直向南行
Just head south.
时速别超过65里
Keep it under 65.
- 我们可不想被交警抓住  - 收到
- We don't want to be pulled over.  - Affirmative.
你必须听听人们怎么说话
You gotta listen to the way people talk.
你不能说"收到"或之类的废话
You don't say "affirmative" or some shit like that.
你要说"没有问题"
You say, "No problemo".
如果某人用很不屑的态度 向你走来 你得说"吃屎吧"
If someone comes off to you with an attitude, you say, "Eat me."
如果你想向人炫耀 就说 "后会有期 宝贝"
And if you want to shine them on, it's "Hasta la vista, baby."
后会有期 宝贝
Hasta la vista, baby.
对 或者是"再会了 麻瓜"
Yeah, or "Later, dick-wad".
某人心烦意乱时 就说"冷静点"
If someone gets upset, you say, "Chill out".
或者你也可以凑起来说
Or you can do combinations.
冷静点 麻瓜
Chill out, dick-wad.
这就对了 看吧? 你开始懂了
That's great. See? You're getting it.
没有问题
No problemo.
你身上有现金吗?
You got any cash?
我这儿有好几百块 可以给你一半
I got a couple hundred bucks. I'll give you half.
妈!
Mom!
买点吃的
Get some food.
真没幽默感
No sense of humor.
还有一件事 你要让自己稍稍阳光一点
That's another thing. You can lighten up a bit yourself.
一本正经 例行公事 实在很无聊
This severe routine is getting old, okay.
我是说 你表现得就像个怪物
I mean, you're acting like such a geek.
时不时微笑一下
Smile once in a while.
微笑?
Smile?
对啊 微笑 看着
Yeah, you know, smile. Watch.
嗨 不错的地方 生意如何?
Hi. Nice place you got here. How's business?
别碍着我
Give me a break.
好吧 错误的示范
Okay, bad example.
看到那边那个家伙了吗?
See that guy over there?
那就是微笑
That's a smile.
(动态选择)
(分析中)
很不错
That's good.
也许 你该在镜子前再练练什么的
Maybe you could practice in front of a mirror or something.
要不要吃点薯条?
Want some of my fries?
需要帮忙吗?
Need any help?
不用
No.
- 我抓到你了!  - 不 才没有!
- I got you!  - No, you didn't!
我们办不到的 对吧?
We're not gonna make it, are we?
我是指 人们
People, I mean.
以邻为壑是人类的天性
It's in your nature to destroy yourselves.
嗯 接受这样的教育 哈?
Yeah. Major drag, huh?
在我扭断你们的脖子前别玩了
Break it up before I wring both of your necks.
我得知道天网是如何建造的
I need to know how Skynet gets built.
谁是负责人?
Who's responsible?
主要负责人是迈尔斯·本尼特·戴森
The man most directly responsible is Miles Bennett Dyson.
他是谁?
Who is that?
他是赛博坦系统公司的特别计划主管
He's the director of special projects at Cyberdyne Systems Corporation.
为什么是他?
Why him?
几个月后 他创造了 一款革命性的微处理器
In a few months he creates a revolutionary type of microprocessor.
继续说 然后呢?
Go on. Then what?
三年内 赛博坦将会变成...
In three years, Cyberdyne will become the largest supplier...
军事电脑系统的最大供应商
of military computer systems.
所有隐形轰炸机采用赛博坦电脑...
All Stealth bombers are upgraded with Cyberdyne computers...
渐渐变成无人驾驶的战斗机
becoming fully unmanned.
然后以完美的操作记录飞行
Afterwards they fly with a perfect operational record.
建造天网的基金法案通过了
The Skynet funding bill is passed.
在1997年8月4日 系统正式启用
The system goes on-line on August 4, 1997.
由于战略防御措施 人类斗志消散
Human decisions are removed from strategic defense.
天网以几何倍数的速率开始学习
Skynet begins to learn at a geometric rate.
在东部时间 8月29日早上2:14 它变得具有自我意识
It becomes self-aware at 2:14 a.m. Eastern time, August 29.
在一阵恐慌中 他们想把电源拔掉
In a panic, they try to pull the plug.
- 天网便开始反击  - 对的
- Skynet fights back.  - Yes.
它向俄国境内的目标发射了核弹
It launches its missiles against the targets in Russia.
为什么攻击俄国人? 他们不是盟国吗?
Why attack Russia? Aren't they our friends now?
因为天网知道俄国人的反击...
Because Skynet knows that the Russian counterattack...
可以消灭它在当地的所有敌人
will eliminate its enemies over here.
老天
Jesus.
你对戴森了解多少?
How much do you know about Dyson?
我有详细的资料
I have detailed files.
我要知道所有的事
I want to know everything.
他长相如何 他住哪里 一切资料
What he looks like, where he lives, everything.
迈尔斯
Miles.
你打算要工作一整天吗?
You gonna to work all day?
我很抱歉 宝贝 但这东西一直在烦我
I'm sorry, baby. But this thing is just kicking my ass.
迈尔斯 今天是星期日
Miles, it's Sunday.
你答应今天带孩子们去水上乐园玩的
You promised to take the kids to Raging Waters today.
我没办法...
I can't...
我就差临门一脚
I'm on a roll.
宝贝 我一走的话将功亏一篑
Baby, this is going to blow them all away.
- 它是一个神经网络处理器  - 我知道 你告诉过我
- It's a neural net processor.  - I know. You told me.
它可以像人类一般思考及学习
It's a neural net processor. It thinks and learns like we do.
它在室温条件下就具备超级处理性能
It's superconducting at room temperature.
其他的电脑 相形之下 只能算是口袋型计算器
Other computers are just pocket calculators by comparison.
但为什么这该死的东西那么重要？
But why is that so goddamn important, Miles?
我真的想知道...
I really need to know...
因为有时 我觉得自己都快抓狂了
because sometimes I feel like I'm going crazy here.
宝贝 我就快接近完成了
Baby, I am this close.
过来
Come here.
想像一台大型喷气式客机...
Imagine a jet airliner...
由一名永不疲倦 永不犯错的飞行员驾驶...
with a pilot that never gets tired, never makes mistakes...
更别说会睡眼惺忪的去上班
never shows up to work with a hangover.
就是这位飞行员
Meet the pilot.
为什么我们要结婚？为什么我们还要生小孩？
Why did we get married, Miles? Why did we have these children?
你根本不需要我们
You don't need us.
你的心思及精神都放在这上面了
Your heart and your mind are in here.
但是它不会像我们一样的爱你
But it doesn't love you like we do.
我很抱歉 真的
I'm sorry. Really.
为什么不多花上一点时间 陪陪你的另一些宝贝?
How about spending some time with your other babies?
雷霆水上乐园!
Raging Waters!
在车里等着
Wait in the car.
恩利科？你在吗？
你很神经质啊 康纳
You're pretty jumpy, Connor.
你也是
You too.
过得怎么样？
- 很高兴见到你，康纳   - 我答应过会再回来的
我可老是在这里埋伏着
尤兰达，快出来，有客人来了，顺便再拿些龙舌兰酒出来！
嘿 约翰
Hey, big John.
过得怎么样?
What's up?
你的朋友是谁？
他没问题 他跟我们一起的
He's cool, Enrique. He's with me.
他是...鲍伯叔叔
He's...Uncle Bob.
鲍伯叔叔 这位是恩利科
Uncle Bob, this is Enrique.
鲍伯叔叔 嗯?
Uncle Bob, huh?
好啊
Okay.
- 好久不见   - 好久不见
都长这么高啦…
喝酒吗?
Drink?
“鲍伯叔叔”?
"Uncle Bob"?
这下你出名了 电视上各频道都在播
You're pretty famous, all over the goddamn TV.
你 约翰 还有你大朋友的照片
Pictures of you, John, your big friend here.
警察像发疯似的到处找你
Cops are going nuts looking for you.
我是来拿家伙的 我需要 衣服 食物以及一辆卡车
I just came for my stuff. I need clothes, food and a truck.
要不要还要我牙缝里的东西?
How about the fillings in my teeth?
现在就要
Now, Enrique.
你们两个负责去检查武器
You two, you're on weapons detail.
来吧 我们走
Come on. Let's go.
关于我妈有件事...
One thing about my mom...
她老是预先计划
she always plans ahead.
好极了
Excellent.
这是我最好的卡车了 但是发动装置不见了
This is the best truck I got, but the starter motor's gone.
有空等我换好它吗?
You got time to change it out?
当然 我要等天黑后再穿越边界
Yeah. I'm gonna wait 'til dark to cross the border.
恩利科
Enrique.
你们留在这里很危险 今晚也离开 好吗?
It's dangerous for you here. You get out tonight too, okay?
好的
Sure.
随便找上个时间来拜访 然后彻底搞乱我的生活 对吧?
Just drop by anytime and totally fuck up my life, all right?
你瞧 我在这样的地方长大...
See, I grew up in places like this...
所以我就认为 这就是人们 如何过活的方式...
so I just thought that's how people lived...
搭着直升机四处乱飞...
riding around in helicopters...
学习如何扔狗屎炸弹
learning how to blow shit up.
但是当我妈被逮捕后...
But then when my mom got busted...
我被送进了正规学校
I got put into a regular school.
其他的小孩都在玩任天堂
All the other kids were into Nintendo.
你曾感到害怕吗?
Are you ever afraid?
不
No.
即使快死了也不会?
Not even of dying?
不会
No.
你对这档子事没有任何感觉 还是对别的什么事有感觉?
You don't feel any emotion about it, one way or another?
没有 我必须保持机能 正常运作 直至任务完成
No. I have to stay functional until my mission is complete.
这之后 就无关紧要了
Then it doesn't matter.
对啊 我也得保持机能正常 运作 因为我"太重要了"
I have to stay functional too. "I'm too important."
看起来真配你
That's definitely you.
大部份跟我妈在一起的人都是怪胎...
Most of the guys my mom hung around with were geeks...
但是有一个家伙 他挺酷的
but there was this one guy, he was kinda cool.
他教我引擎的原理
He taught me engines.
抓住这里
Hold here.
当然啦 妈又搞砸了
Mom screwed it up, of course.
她常常告诉他们关于审判日的事...
She'd always tell 'em about Judgment Day...
而我会是这世界的领袖
and me being this world leader.
她总是这么说着
That'd be all she wrote.
请递转矩板手给我
Torque wrench, please.
拿去
Here.
我希望我能遇见真正的父亲
I wish I could've met my real dad.
你会的
You will.
对呀 我猜也是
Yeah, I guess.
当我大概45岁时吧 我想
When I'm, like, 45, I think.
我把他送至1984年
They sent him back through time to 1984.
好家伙
Man.
他那时甚至还未出生
He hasn't even been born yet.
这会让你头脑混乱
It messes with your head.
- 另一个螺栓  - 喔 给
- The other bolt.  - Oh. Here.
妈跟他在一起才一个晚上
Mom and him were only together for one night.
我猜她还爱着他
She still loves him, I guess.
我有时看到她在哭
I see her crying sometimes.
她当然完全不承认 就说有东西飞进她的眼睛
She denies it totally, of course, like she got something stuck in her eye.
你们为什么会哭?
Why do you cry?
- 你是指人们为什么会哭?  - 对
- You mean people?  - Yeah.
我不知道
I don't know.
我们就是会哭...
We just cry...
你知道 当有伤痛时
you know, when it hurts.
痛苦造成的吗?
Pain causes it?
不 那是两码事
No. It's different.
当你没有任何不对劲 但你就是觉得内心悲痛
It's when there's nothing wrong with you, but you hurt anyway.
- 你懂吗?  - 不懂
- You get it?  - No.
好极了 我的伙计!
All right, my man!
没有问题
No problemo.
给我五
Give me five.
就把你的手放成这样
Just put out your hand like this.
对了! 现在打回来 击掌 照着做
All right! Now hit me. Give me five. Do the same thing.
好 这就对了
Okay, that's good. Up high.
低手击掌
Five low.
太慢了
Too slow.
只是开个玩笑 再来一次
I'm just kidding. One more time.
很好 现在试试这个
Good. Now try it.
现在换我 给我个五
Now do me. Give me five.
看着约翰跟那机器在一起 思绪忽然清晰起来
Watching John with the machine, it was suddenly so clear.
终结者永远不会停止运行
The Terminator would never stop.
不会离开他 也永远不会伤害他...
It would never leave him, an he would never hurt him...
不会对他大吼大叫 酒醉揍他...
never shout at him or get drunk and hit him...
或者是太忙而没空陪他
or be too busy to spend time with him.
它会永远在他身边...
lt would always be there...
至死都会保护他
and it would die to protect him.
纵观所有来去数年 将成为John继父的人...
Of all the would-be fathers who came and went over the years...
这东西 这个机器...
this thing, this machine...
是唯一符合标准的
was the only one who measured up.
在这个疯狂的世界里...
In an insane world...
这是一个疯狂的抉择
it was the sanest choice.
我们来玩玩这个
Hey, let's try this one.
坐上来啰
There we go.
(命运不存在)
她关照说你跟他向南行 按计划
She said go south with him like you planned.
- 她明天会跟你们会合  - 妈!
- She'll meet you tomorrow.  - Mom!
妈 等一下!
Mom, wait!
“命运不存在”
"No fate."
命运是由自己创造的
No fate but what we make.
我父亲告诉她的
My father told her this.
我是说 在未来我嘱咐他 要记下并转达给她的讯息
I mean I made him memorize it in the future as a message to her.
算了
Never mind.
好吧 整件事是...
Okay, the whole thing goes...
未来尚未定数
The future's not set.
命运并不存在 要靠自己创造
There's no fate but what we make for ourselves.
她打算要改变未来
She intends to change the future.
对 我猜是这样
Yeah, I guess.
哦 糟了!
Oh, shit!
- 戴森  - 对
- Dyson.  - Yeah.
一定是迈尔斯·戴森
Gotta be. Miles Dyson.
她要去杀了他
She's gonna blow him away.
快点! 我们走!
Come on! Let's go!
就战术上来说 这很危险
This is tactically dangerous.
开快一点
Drive faster.
T-1000拥有与我相同的资料
The T-1000 has the same files that I do.
我知道的 他全都知道 它可能会预料到这一招
It knows what I know. It might anticipate this move.
我不管 我们得阻止她
I don't care. We gotta stop her.
杀了Dyson可能会避免战争发生
Killing Dyson maybe actually prevent the war.
我才不在乎呢!
I don't care!
你还是学不会吗?
Haven't you learned anything yet?
你有没有想过 为什么你不可以杀人?
Haven't you figured out why you can't kill people?
听着 也许你不在乎是死是活...
Look, maybe you don't care if you live or die...
但不是每个人都会这样
but everybody's not like that.
我们拥有感情 会受伤 会恐惧
We have feelings. We hurt. We're afraid.
这点你要牢记 我说真的 这很重要
You got to learn this stuff. I'm not kidding. It's important.
丹尼 我告诉过你 得跟姐姐一样上床睡觉了
Danny, I told you to go to bed, like your sister.
再等一下 妈!
Just a couple of minutes, Mom!
丹尼 上床时间到了!
Danny, your time is up!
快来刷牙 然后去睡觉
Come brush your teeth and get to bed.
丹尼!
Danny!
爸爸!
Daddy!
丹尼 快走! 快走!
Danny, go! Go!
迈尔斯?
Miles?
- 托西娅 快走!  - 我的天哪!
- Tarissa, run!  - Oh, my God!
快带丹尼离开!
Just take Danny and run!
快跑!
Run!
老天呀! 迈尔斯!
Oh, Jesus! Miles!
爸爸!
Daddy!
任何人都不准动!
Nobody fucking move!
别伤害我爸!
Don't hurt my daddy!
趴在地上 婊子
On the floor, bitch.
现在就趴在地上!
Get down now!
让开!
Get out of the way!
别伤害他!
Don't hurt him!
现在就趴在地上!
Get on the floor now!
求你让小孩走
Just let the boy go.
闭嘴 闭嘴
Shut up. Shut up.
给我闭嘴!
Shut up!
一切都是你的错 你这畜生
It's all your fault, motherfucker.
- 都是你的错!  - 什么?
- It's all your fault!  - What?
我不会让你这样做的
I'm not gonna let you do it.
该死! 我们慢了一步!
Shit! We're too late!
检查他们
Check them.
看着我 妈
Look at me, Mom.
你没受伤吧?
Are you hurt?
我差点就...
I almost...
没事了
It'll be okay.
我们会想出办法的 好吗?
We'll figure something out. Okay?
我保证
I promise.
你是来阻止我的
You came here to stop me.
对呀 没错
Yeah, I did.
我爱你 约翰
I love you, John.
永远爱你
I always have.
我知道
I know.
子弹穿过身体
Deep penetration.
没有打碎骨头
No shattered bone.
握紧这里 施压可以止血
Hold here. The pressure should stop the bleeding.
你们是什么人?
Who are you people?
给他看看
Show him.
丹尼 我希望你跟我来 带我去你的房间 好吗
Danny, I want you to come with me right now. Show me your room.
噢 上帝啊
Oh, my God.
现在给我仔细听好了
Now listen to me very carefully.
戴森仔细聆听 终结者全盘托出
Dyson listened while the Terminator laid it all down.
天网 审判日
Skynet. Judgment Day.
整件事的由来
The history of things to come.
你不是每天都会发现你必须为...
It's not every day that you find out you're responsible...
30亿人的死亡负责
for three billion deaths.
他差不多理解了
He took it pretty well.
我觉得我快吐了
I feel like I'm gonna throw up.
你以我还未做的事...
You're judging me...
审判我的过失
on things I haven't even done yet.
我们怎知会变成这样?
How were we supposed to know?
对啊
Yeah.
没错
Right.
你们怎么会知道?
How were you supposed to know?
一群像你一样的人渣...
Fucking men like you...
建造了氢弹
built the hydrogen bomb.
像你一样的家伙...
Men like you...
投下了它
thought it up.
你们自认为很有创造力吗
You think you're so creative.
你们根本不知什么是真正的创造...
You don't know what it's like to really create something...
去创造生命...
to create a life...
感受它在你体内成长
to feel it growing inside you.
你们只知道如何创造死亡及毁灭万物
All you know how to create is death and destruction.
妈!
Mom!
我们要做点有建设性的事 好吗?
We need to be a little more constructive here. Okay?
我们还得阻止这一切发生 对吗?
We still have to stop this from happening, don't we?
但是我想...
But I thought...
我们不是正在改变一切? 改变它未来的发展?
Aren't we changing things? I mean right now, changing the way it goes?
没错 打死我也不想完成 那处理器了 至少现在不
That's right. There's no way I'm going to finish the new processor. Not now.
算了 我退出 我明天就辞职
Forget it. I'm out of it. I'll quit Cyberdyne tomorrow.
这样还不够
That's not good enough.
得确保没人接替你的工作
No one must follow your work.
对
Right.
好吧 那我们得摧毁实验室里的所有东西...
All right, then we have to destroy all the stuff at the lab...
文件 磁盘...
the files, the disk drives...
在里面的所有东西
everything here.
完完全全的摧毁
Everything.
我不在乎了
I don't care.
那块芯片
The chip.
- 你知道那块芯片吗?  - 什么芯片?
- Do you know about the chip?  - What chip?
在公司里 来自一个 与你相同的机器人
It's at Cyberdyne. It's from the other one like you.
第一代终结者的中央处理器
The CPU from the first Terminator.
他妈的! 我就知道!
Son of a bitch! I knew it!
他们说别问这是从哪弄来的
They told us not to ask where they got it.
那些说谎的畜生
Those lying motherfuckers.
这是个很惊人的东西 十分先进
It's scary stuff. Radically advanced.
有点破碎
It was smashed.
不能用了 但它给了我们一些启发 带领我们进入新的领域
It didn't work, but it gave us ideas, took us in new directions.
一些我们从来不会...
I mean things we would've never...
我所有的工作 都是以它为基础的
All my work was based on it.
它必须被摧毁掉
It must be destroyed.
你能带我们通过警卫 进入实验室吗?
Can you get us in, Past security?
我想可以 什么时候?
I think so, yeah. When?
现在?
Now?
未来如此清晰地展现在我的面前...
The future, always so clear to me...
像是变成一条暗夜里的黑色公路
had become like a black highway at night.
我们现正步入未知的领域...
We were in uncharted territory now...
一路走下去 写下历史
making up history as we went along.
卡尔 没记错吧?
Carl, right?
城外来的朋友 我只是想我能否...
Friends from out of town. I just thought I'd...
带他们上楼参观一下
take 'em upstairs and show 'em around.
戴森先生 你明知道 参观实验室的相关规定
Mr. Dyson, you know the rules concerning visitors in the lab.
必须要有书面的经授权的文件...
I need written authorization...
我坚持要参观
I insist.
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
这里没人
It's okay.
需要两把钥匙 同时转动 以打开保险库
It takes two keys, turned simultaneously, to open the vault.
另一把在安全室的柜子里
The other one is in a locker at the security station.
吉布斯?
Gibbons?
吉布斯! 你在哪里 老兄!
Gibbons! Come on, man!
你不可以擅离职守!
You can't leave the desk like that!
糟糕
Oh, shit.
我的卡应该可以开启的
My card should access this.
- 怎么了?  - 该死
- What is it?  - Damn it.
静音警报已经启动了
The silent alarm's been tripped.
这使得整栋大楼里的通关密码失效
It's neutralized all the codes in the entire building.
现在任何东西都打不开了
Nothing will open anywhere now.
我们得放弃行动
We have to abort.
不行
No.
一定要完成 好吗?
We go all the way. Okay?
你们先去搞定实验室 这我能打开
You guys get started on the lab. I can open this.
- 我想是购物中心的那个家伙  - 真的是他
- I think it's that guy from the mall.  - It is.
是他和那个女人
It's him and the woman.
快派遣这地区你能调来的所有警力
Just send everything you got in the area right now.
我有进实验室的个人 密码 也许还能用
I have a personal entry code for the lab. It may still work.
也不行
It's no good.
让我试试我的方法
Let me try mine.
约翰 小心要爆炸了!
John, fire in the hole!
等一下! 不能直接走进去 火源会引发海龙消防系统
Wait! You can't go in there. The fire set off the Halon system.
必须等几分钟 直到气体排空
You have to wait until the gas clears.
戴上这个
Put this on.
好了 开始行动吧
All right, let's get to work.
附近地区以及能回应的所有单位...
All units in the vicinity and all units able to respond...
211状况 克雷姆街2144号 赛博坦大楼
a 211 in progress, 2144 Kramer Street, the Cyberdyne building.
一名嫌犯是白人女性...
Suspect one is white female...
经查证姓名为莎拉康纳
identified as last name Connor, first name Sarah.
昨晚自皮斯卡德罗州立医院出逃
Escaped last night from Pescadero State Hospital.
第二名嫌犯: 白人男性...
Suspect two: White male...
所有在我办公室里的磁盘...
All the disks in my office...
在那边的一间办公室里...
all the disks in that office over there...
我办公桌后面的所有东西...
everything behind my desk...
以及左边的那些主机
and all the processors on my left.
我们会用CP4炸药炸掉这些
We'll blow those with the CP4.
我能不能...
Can I...
对不起
Excuse me.
能不能借我用一下?
Can I borrow that thing?
我在这东西上花了好几年心思
I worked a lot of years on this thing.
1-玛丽23号 再说一次地点
One-Mary-23, give me that location again.
克雷姆街2111号
2111 Kramer.
嫌犯持有武器而且判定为极度危险
Suspects are armed and considered extremely dangerous.
好了
All right.
7-2-5-6
7-2-5-6.
容易来的钱
Easy money.
哦喔 糟了
Oh, shit. Not good.
进展如何?
How we doing?
电线已经接好
Primer cord is set.
还有一桶 再有2分多钟完毕
One more barrel, two more minutes.
- 我们怎么引爆?  - 用遥控器
- How do we set them off?  - Remote control.
小菜一碟
Piece of cake.
- 我们有伴了  - 警察吗?
- We got company.  - Police?
- 有多少人?  - 全员出动了 我想
- How many?  - All of 'em, I think.
快走 我来搞定剩下的
Go. I'll finish here.
走吧
Come on.
我会关照那群警察的
I'll take care of the police.
等一下! 你发过誓的!
Wait! You swore!
相信我
Trust me.
在窗边的人!
You at the window!
放下武器 把手放在头上!
Drop your weapon and place your hands on top of your head!
妈的!
Holy shit!
那是一挺Minimi机关枪!(比利时FN公司研制的著名机枪)
That's a mini-gun!
- 快走!  - 该死!
- Come on!  - Oh, shit!
快走! 快走! 快走!
Go! Go! Go!
(人员伤亡)
(人员伤亡:0.0)
开火!
Fire!
同时向左转
Same time, to the left.
一 二 三 转
One, two, three, go.
要把那东西拿出来...
In order to get that out...
我们现在抓到天网的要害了
We got Skynet by the balls now.
走吧 干活
Come on, let's book.
停火!
Hold your fire!
- 准备好大干一场了吗?  - 准备好了
- Ready to rock?  - Ready.
该走了
Time to go.
就现在
Now.
- 拿着这个 他们会使用催泪瓦斯  - 来吧
- Take this. They'll use gas.  - Come on.
从门先开始 迈尔斯 把引爆器拿给我
Get started on the door. Miles, hand me the detonator.
妈! 妈!
Mom! Mom!
该死!
Shit!
该死! 她在消毒室 那里没有出口
Shit! She's in the clean room. There's no way outta there.
趴下!
Get down!
给
Here.
我不知道我还能撑得了多久
I don't know how much longer I can hold this.
撤退!
Fall back!
大家快出去!
Everybody out!
马上撤退! 快走! 快走! 快走!
Fall back now! Go! Go! Go!
这里变成战场了!
We got a war zone here!
(威胁评估)
闭上眼睛
Shut your eyes.
待在这里 我马上回来
Stay here. I'll be back.
趴在地上! 脸朝下!
Get down on the floor! Face down!
快趴在地上!
On the floor now!
好 干掉他!
Okay, drop him!
你 拿着
Here, hold this.
他妈的!
Holy shit!
开车!
Go!
该死!
Shit!
滚下去
Get out.
听着
Listen.
不管发生什么事 都躲在防弹衣后
No matter what happens, you stay under these vests.
- 懂了吗?  - 懂了
- You got it?  - Yeah.
很好
Great.
直升机追上来了!
Chopper's coming in!
是他
It's him.
要命!
Shit!
躲好!
Stay down!
哦 天哪!
Goddamn!
你没事吧...
You all right...
快点 妈 我们快离开
Come on, Mom, we gotta get out.
拿着霰弹枪
Take the shotgun.
受伤了吗?
Are you hurt?
(液态氮)
他妈的
Holy shit.
快呀 妈 快点!
Come on, Mom. Come on!
我们要用你的卡车
We need your truck.
快走!
Hurry!
- 来吧 快点  - 上车
- Come on. Hurry.  - Get in.
快上来!
Go!
搞什么...
What the hell...
- 伤口流血很多  - 用力压住
- I'm bleeding bad.  - Keep pressure on it.
用这个止血
Here. This'll work.
他追上来了
He's gaining.
快踩油门!
Step on it!
- 这辆车只能开这么快  - 我光跑步都比这要快!
- This is the vehicle's top speed.  - I can run faster than this!
他追上了 在右边
Coming up, to the right.
小心! 小心!
Watch it! Watch it!
- 你来开车  - 你要去哪?
- Drive.  - Where are you going?
开下匝道
Take the off-ramp.
该死!
Shit!
抓稳了!
Hold on!
别停!
Don't stop!
直走!
Go straight!
小心!
Look out!
低头!
Duck!
大家快离开这里!
Get the hell outta here!
快离开! 走呀! 快点!
Get outta here! Let's go! Come on!
后会有期 宝贝
Hasta la vista, baby.
我们没多少时间了
We don't have much time.
我们走
Let's go.
我们得离开这里
We gotta get outta here.
快点! 站起来!
Come on! Get up!
把霰弹枪递给我
Hand me the shotgun.
妈 让我来扶你 来吧
Put your weight on me, Mom.
快走!
Hurry!
加油 妈
Come on, Mom.
快起来!
Get up!
走这边 来吧
This way. Come on.
等一下! 不 不 这里太热了
Wait! No. No. It's too hot.
走回来
Go back.
- 走 快逃  - 不要! 我们要呆在一起
- Go. Run.  - No! We gotta stick together.
约翰 你得快点离开
John, you've got to go now.
- 约翰!  - 快走! 现在!
- John!  - Go! Now!
(搜索模式)
上楼梯
Get up the steps.
走
Go.
上去
Get up.
妈 我扶住你了 快点
Come on, Mom. I got you.
抓住铁链 抓好
Grab the chain. Grab it.
抓着 走 快下去!
Grab it. Go. Go!
妈 快来! 妈!
Mom, come on! Mom!
叫约翰出来
Call to John.
我知道这样很痛
I know this hurts.
叫John的名字
Call John.
快叫他出来 现在
Call to John now.
去你的
Fuck you.
(输送)
(备用能源)
帮帮我!
Help!
妈
Mom.
帮帮我
Help me.
快让开 John
Get out of the way, John.
开枪!
Shoot!
趴下!
Get down!
起来 快点
Get up. Come on.
太糟糕了
Holy shit.
我需要休假
I need a vacation.
它死了吗?
Is it dead?
被终结了
Terminated.
这也熔得掉吗?
Will this melt in there?
对 把它丢进去
Yes. Throw it in.
永别了
Adios.
还有芯片
And the chip.
一切都结束了
It's over.
不
No.
还有另一块芯片
There's one more chip.
它也必须被销毁
And it must be destroyed also.
这里
Here.
我无法自我终结掉 你把我送进钢液里
I cannot self-terminate. You must lower me into the steel.
我很抱歉 约翰 我很抱歉
I'm sorry, John. I'm sorry.
不要 这没关系的 和我们一起留下来
No, it'll be okay. Stay with us.
- 会没事的  - 我得走了
- It'll be okay.  - I have to go away.
别这样 请别走
No, don't do it. Please, don't go.
我不能留下来
I must go away, John.
不 等一下
No, wait.
你不需要这样做
You don't have to do this.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不 不要这样! 别走!
No, don't do it! Don't go!
一切必须在此终结
It has to end here.
我命令你不准走!
I order you not to go!
我现在知道你们为什么会哭了
I know now why you cry.
但这是我永远不会做的
But it's something I can never do.
再见
Goodbye.
我们的末来不可预知
The unknown future rolls toward us.
但我第一次对末来充满期望
I face it for the first time with a sense of hope.
因为如果一台机器，如终结者
Because if a machine, a Terminator..
都能学会人类自身的价值
can learn the value of human life...
也许，我们也可以
maybe we can too.